# **Erin Yoo**

San Francisco, CA 954-551-8441 hello@erinyoo.com erinyoo.com

## **My Objective**

Innovative and empathetic professional committed to pursuing a long-term career change into product design. Offers two years experience as a front end developer demonstrating critical problem-solving skills, experience seeing a feature through from inception to completion, and building strong collaboration skills with designers on the team.

## **Skills**

Investigate	Design & Tools	Dev
Storyboarding, Personas,	Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop,	HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
Usability Testing, Wireframing	Procreate	React, Redux

## **Work Experience**

**Product Designer** Apr 2023-present

- Exploring how to make it easier to connect someone to help answer a question.
- Utilizing design thinking and learning to master Figma.

### Software Engineer II Dec 2021-Apr 2023

- Led a feature team to successfully ship an initial frontend iteration for the new Viva Engage Answers platform internally and navigated multi-stage release process.
- Mentored all new engineers on the team, transferred key knowledge of Yammer's technical processes, and taught key skills for professional growth.
- Engaged in the design process end to end, participated in user interviews and worked with designers to iterate on design proposals to ensure technically sound user focused design.
- Coordinated cross functionally with various product teams to align all stakeholders and maximize efficiency of engineering and design efforts.

### Software Engineer May 2020-Dec 2021

- Gained valuable experience working on an agile team.
- Worked in and with TypeScript, React, Redux, GraphQL.

#### **Education**

**B.S. in Computer Science** University of Florida